<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
<a rel="me" href="https://fosstodon.org/@koreymoffett"></a>
<channel>
<title>Korey's Blog</title>
<description>Updates from Korey.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/rss.xml</link>
<atom:link href="https://koreymoffett.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<image>
<title>Korey's Blog</title>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/rss.xml</link>
</image>

<item>
<title>Switching to Emacs</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/switching-to-emacs</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/switching-to-emacs</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="title">Switching to Emacs</h1>
            <h1 class="subtitle">Doom-Emacs</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">I first started coding about 2 years ago off and on as nothing serious, just as a way to tinker about with my computer when I was at home, but as I started to get deeper and deeper into the rabbit hole that is coding I started to look for
                a serious text editor. When I first started I was using a program called Atom to edit my code(you may have heard of it, the text editor made by github).
                <br> I looked online and saw many people used Atom and that Github was the creater of it so it seemed like a no-brainer. Since then however I have tried nearly every editor under the sun, I tried Atom, Sublime Text, VSCode(Still use some),
                and Vim and I must say most of them were a complete let down.
                <br> For example, When I used Sublime i was always so annoyed by it's keybinding and it's just rather dull design. With Atom, it was great for awhile until it started really slowing down do to the number of add-ons I had and needed for
                the projects I was working on. For Vim and VSCode, These two actually haven't let me down they have been amazing since the day I started using them, but I think it's time to give Emacs a fair chance.
                <br> I always hated on Emacs, saying 'This program has the most idiotic key binds/key-chords', then i found Doom-Emacs(Thanks DistroTube). I have only been using Doom-Emacs for about two hours and I can whole heartly say I love it. Because
                it's Vim, VSCode and Emacs all smashed into one package.
                <br> If you have been looking for a terminal based or GUI text editor that's pretty lightweight but still has all the features you will ever need, I highly recommend Doom-Emacs.

            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Happy Holidays</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/happy-holidays</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/happy-holidays</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
 <h1 class="title">Merry Christmas Everyone</h1>
            <h1 class="subtitle">Happy Holidays</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">It's Christmas today! Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays to everyone.
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>I'll never buy a Mac</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/ill-never-buy-mac</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/ill-never-buy-mac</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
  <h1 class="title">Why I'll never buy a Mac</h1>
            <h1 class="subtitle">Never again</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">I don't have some horror story of my keyboard breaking or my screen just dying on me, in fact my macbook has held up pretty good. But I have since learned about Linux and after installing Linux on my desktop I see absolutly no reason for Apple
                to even make computers at all to be honestly(Other than to make money but that's obvious.).
                <br> Macs try to fill this really weird area of computing that I just don't see a purpose for. For anything you need to do you can use Linux or Windows and they will do the job better in many cases (other than make apps for iphone and
                mac)
                <br>
                <br> Macs are just super expensive computers with lowend specs, and about 80% of the price you paid for that mac is so you can have that Apple logo on the back.
                <br> I'm not someone who buys a new laptop every year in fact I wait until the laptop has more than one issue to buy a new one in most cases, but I can say with 100% certainty that I will never buy another apple computer rather it be a
                laptop or a desktop mac ever again.
                <br>
                <br> Linux is my prefered OS to compute on.
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Why use FOSS?</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/foss</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/foss</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="title">Why use FOSS?</h1>
            <h1 class="subtitle">Why should you care?</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">I guess first I should start of by explaining what FOSS is, FOSS is Free and Open Source Software.
                <br> For a program or software to be consitered free(as in freedom, has nothing to do with price.) it first has to meet the four essential freedoms.
                <br>
                <br>
                <ul>
                    <li>Freedom 0: The freedom to run the program as you wish, for any purpose.<li>
                        <li>Freedom 1: The freedom to study how the program works, and change it so it does your computing as you wish.</li>
                        <li>Freedom 2: The freedom to redistribute copies so you can help others.</li>
                        <li>Freedoom 3: The freedom to distribute copies of your modified verison to others. By doing this you can give the whole community a chance to benefit from your changes. Access to the source code is a necessity.</li>
                </ul>
                <br>
                <br>
                Now, to answer the question, "Why should you care about FOSS?"<br>
                You should truly care about FOSS because unlike most software/programs, FOSS won't collect data about you to sell to the highest bidder, but it also gives you the freedom to change the things you don't like about the program or to change the things you need to change to be able to use the program. For example lets say there is a program that someone needs to use but they can't read the font size due to a vision impairment, Well with FOSS they could easily change the font size because they have access to the source code. Not only that but you can also have the peace of mind that the program isn't sending your information to people or companies who have no real reason to see your information.
                <br>
                <br>
                Supporting FOSS is supporting Freedom!
                <br>
                <hr>
                Please consider donating your time or donating financially to these organizations to help push FOSS forward:
                <br>
                <br>
                <a href="https://www.fsf.org/">Free Software Foundation<a>
                    <br>
                    <a href="https://www.eff.org/">Electronic Frontier Foundation<a>
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Distro hopping is pointless</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/distro-hopping</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/distro-hopping</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="title">Distro Hopping</h1>
            <h1 class="subtitle">We all do it but it's dumb</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                In the Linux world there is a term you will hear thrown around a lot and that "Distro hop" or "Distro hopping", as the name suggests this is when someone installs distribution after distibution expecting to find that perfect one.
                <br>
                Distro hopping just out of curiosity isn't bad in my personaly opinion, but I think constantly wiping your hard drive(ssd in most cases these days) is pointless.
                <br>
                Finding that magic linux distro isn't going to happen, none of them are perfect and anything you don't like about the distro you are currently running(or thinking about running) is easily changable.
                The only real reason I can see for distro hopping is say for example you are running ubuntu and you want something more minimal you could install something like Debian or Arch other than that there isn't much purpose in it.
                <br>
                <br>
                I myself have been that new to linux user who want to try the newest shiny thing he sees but it really is a massive waste of time, energy and can be damaging to your workflow as well.
                <br>
                <br>
                I recently made the switch to base debian as I wanted a more minimal system and so far I have had zero issues. Debian is rock solid and thats why I love it.
                Sure it may not have the lastest packages, but you when you install a package you can know for a fact it will work, unlike with arch.
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Stop Using Twitter!</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/stop-using-twitter</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/stop-using-twitter</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2021 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="title">Stop Using Twitter!</h1>
            <h1 class="subtitle">and other freedom hating platforms.</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                As you my know recently platforms like Twitter, Facebook, Snapchat and many others have been recently banning and removing anyone they disagree with rather it's a political belief or
                your favorite breakfast cereal Big Tech has shown that it can defy the laws and do what it wants.
                <br>
                <br>
                If you are looking for some alternatives to those freedom hating platforms here are a few.
                <br>
                <br>
                <ul>
                    <li><a href="joinmastodon.org">Mastodon</a></li> - Twitter like but completly federated. I personaly am on the fosstodon instance.
                    <li><a href="lbry.tv">LBRY</a>/<a href="odysee.com">Odysee</a></li> - This can replace Youtube and even has a neat crypto system to tip the creators, both of these are the same things they just have diffrent UI
                    <li><a href="signal.org">Signal</a></li> - This isn't a free and open source application but if you are still using whatsapp or any other facebook trash this is a good replacemant and lets you encrypt your messages.
                </ul>
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>What is Mastodon</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/mastodon</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/mastodon</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
 <h1 class="title">What is Mastodon</h1>
            <h1 class="subtitle">the elephant is better than the bird.</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                If you read <a href="stop-using-twitter">Stop Using Twitter!</a> you my recall that I mentioned something called Mastodon
                Mastodon is a social site that allows users to set up instances and microblog comparable to Twitter.
                However the benifits to Mastodon far outweigh anything twitter has to offer.
                <br>
                Mastodon is a federated social site meaning there is no central rule book or agenda being followed.
                <br>
                The users will join an instance that best suits there intrests or there intrest leading to communities being built around a common intrest.
                You may think it's a bad thing that there are no central rules to the site but let me explain, each instance has it's own rules.
                <br>
                For example some instances may not allow users to use foul language and some may fully allow it.
                <br>
                <br>
                The beauty of a site like Mastodon is that even if your instance kicks you, you can still go join another instance with the same account.
                <br>
                If you were on mstdon.social and they decided they don't like what you are posting or maybe you broke the rules and kick you, you could go join fosstodon.org (which is the instance im in).
                As you can see just from the very few point I actully talked about mastodon does still have a way of regulating itself and dealing with the trolls.
                <br>
                <br>
                <hr>
                If you are intrested in joining up on mastodon and have a love for FOSS(Free and Open Source Software)
                I would highly recommend joining <a href="https://fosstodon.org">Fosstodon</a> I have been here for a few months now and I have had a very good time.
                <br>
                It's actually like a little community of some pretty cool people.
                <br>
                <br>
                If you aren't into FOSS but still want to join mastodon i recommend going to <a href="https://instances.social">Matodon Instances</a> here you will find tons of other instances that may suit you better.
                    <br>
                    I hope to see many new toots on mastodon :)  (post on mastodon are called toots i'm not weird or something lol)

            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>


</channel>
</rss>
